<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Home</title>
    <link>https://Venura-94.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://Venura-94.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End-Loan Default Risk Prediction</title>
      <link>https://Venura-94.github.io/post/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Venura-94.github.io/post/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Target Audience Empowering banks with critical insights into factors influencing loan defaults, predictive model aims to refine loan authorization processes and risk assessments.&#xA;Link to GitHub&#xA;Learning Outcomes: Applied machine learning, model creation, error reduction and tuning techniques (supervised learning) Machine Learning Pipelines (Training Pipeline, Prediction pipeline (inference Pipeline)) AWS / Github actions (CI/CD) Docker Python virtual environments Basic web development Flask How to maintain folder architecture for production ready projects Check github to see the pipelines &amp;amp; AWS delpoyment architectures Model Deployment Explanation: Local Development (PC using Git):</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wholesale Distributor Customer Segmentation Analysis to Optimize the Delivery Service &amp; Strategies</title>
      <link>https://Venura-94.github.io/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Venura-94.github.io/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this project, i analyzed a dataset containing data on various customers&amp;rsquo; annual spending amounts across diverse product categories. The goal is to identify distinct customer segments and derive insights to inform business strategies, particularly in optimizing delivery services.&#xA;Data Analysis and Preprocessing Explored the dataset to understand customer spending behavior and preferences. Box-Cox Transformed Outlier Removal Employed techniques like Principal Component Analysis (PCA) to reduce dimensionality and uncover underlying structures.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
